

# MANUEL DAMIAN Senior Software Engineer



manueldamian@outlook.com



+(52) 312 134 5150



ManuelDamian



ManuelDamian

## **BIOGRAPHY**

I am a software engineer whose primary strengths lie in dedication and hard work. Currently, I am interested in the field of web development, using technologies such as JavaScript, React, and SCSS, along with Git and Jira for project development. I have experience in various areas of the IT industry, as well as a strong ability to work collaboratively in a team.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Developer

AgileThought | Aug 2021 - Currently | CDMX, MX

Developing highly adaptive applications based on customer requirements at Citibank.

- AngularJS: Working developing new components within a monotepo app focusing on use profile section depending on user histories.
- Jira: Using jira software to track project user histories.
- Scss: creating beautiful interfaces to improve integration with the end user.
- Github: Using github to storage projects repositories.
- Postman : Testing Apis.

## Software Developer

Freelancer | Jun 2020 - Currently | Colima, MX

Develop custom applications for small and medium businesses. Main responsibilities are project management, application design and front end development.

- Reactjs: Developed applications with react using HTML5,CSS,Javascript,React, from scratch implementing, custom reusable components.
- Api Integration: Integrate REST apis within applications.
- Postman : Testing Apis.
- Github: Using github to storage projects repositories.

# Software Engineer

Softtek | Nov 2019- June 2021 | Guadalajara, MX

Working as a sysadmin at DXC Technologies company as an L2 engineer in charge of internal infrastructure applications.

- Linux Command line.
- Intenal Applications.

# Software Engineer

TCS | May 2017 - Nov 2019 | Guadalajara, MX

Working as a sysadmin at TCS, responsible of applications and environments in a banking project at Morgan Stanley.

- Sockeye: Jobs scheduling
- Linux Command line.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Colima

AUG 2012 - JUn 2016 | Colima, MX

Bachelor Degree in Software Engineering.

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

### **REACTJS**

- Routing.
- Component creation.
- Api integration.

#### SCSS/CSS

- Responsive design.

#### **JIRA**

- Project tracking

#### CONFLUENCE

- Project Documentation

#### **GITHUB**

- Version Control

# LANGUAGES

- ENGLISH
- SPANISH